

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





# MANAS KUMAR DAS ( Featured )





Technical Lead Delivery seeking roles in Software Engineering, SAP Analytics Cloud(SAC), HANA Modeling, BW on HANA/BW4HANA Modeling, Data Provisioning( SLT,BODS,SDA/SDI,ODQ), SAP BW-ABAP and HANA SQL Script, Performance tuning in HANA Artifacts.

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Total Experience: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Kolkata

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Technical Lead, Software Engineering, Solution Analyst, Technical Project Delivery Lead, SAP Analytics Cloud(SAC), HANA Modeling, BW on HANA/BW4HANA Modeling, Data Provisioning (SLT,BÓDS,SDA/SDI,ODQ), SAP BW-ABAP and HANA SQL Script, Performance tuning.

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21

Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

## Summary

Overall 11+ yrs. of SAP Certified professional of implementation and production support experience on various industry verticals like Oil and Gas, Manufacturing , Retail, Telecom and FMCG as SAP BI/BW, BW on HANA, BW/4HANA, HANA Modelling & SAP Analytics Cloud Reporting and onsite experience in Hungary and Canada

Accomplished 5 implementation and 2 support and Enhancements projects during my IT professional experiences. Experience in core SAP Analytics Cloud Capabilities related to Data connectivity (Live /Data import), modeling, visualizations, APIs, collaboration etc.

Experience in Native HANA Experience: Creation of Attribute View, Analytical Views and Calculation Views, Script View, Store Procedure, Table Function, Scalar functions and CDS Views etc.

Experience in Performance tuning of HANA Artifacts

Experience in Data Provisioning: BODS, SLT, SDA, DXC and ODQ/ODP

Experience in ABAP and SAP HANA SQL Script

Experience in BW/BI BW/4HANA Extraction: LO Extraction, FI Extraction.

## **Work Experience**

Accenture India Pvt. Limited as Technical Lead May 2019 to Jul 2020

SAP Analytics Cloud Accountabilities

Hands on experience on Planning, Allocations and VDT (Value Driver Tree).

Hands on experience on building Geo-Maps

Experience in creating Dashboard and Agenda in Digital boardroom.

Experience in creating smart discoveries and machine learning scenarios.

Perform build/development in SAP Analytics cloud as per standards and guidelines.

Ability to drive the functional data integration with Analytical and planning reporting. Good knowledge of data warehousing and visualization concept of reporting.

Create test cases and perform all sort (Unit, Integration, UAT) of testing

# HANA Modeling Accountabilities

Designed and developed HANA models like attribute views, analytic views, and calculation views ,calculated columns, hierarchies and input parameters per the report requirements

Created information models for COPA multidimensional reports that include COPA variance and COPA Actual/Plan comparison reports using SAP HANA Studio.

Created Purchase order details reports using SCM functionality.

Created query views on the virtual data models delivered by HANA Live.

Conducted peer reviews and performance tuning of developed HANA models using best practices.

Performed full life cycle SAP HANA SDLC followed Safe Agile implementation

Expertise in Data modelling, SQL, Stored Procedures Table functions, Analytic Privileges, HDB Tables, UDF Functions

Good knowledge in SAP Web IDE, Multi Target Apps, HDI Containers for Cross container access Scenarios Understanding of CPI-DS/HCI-DS

BW/ BI,BW on HANA/BW4HANA Accountabilities

## **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

vvorked extensively on Data ivodeling design like creating into Objects, Advanced DSO, Composite Provider, Open ODS view

Converted standard BW models into HANA optimized models and imported into SAP HANA

Extensively worked in LO-Cockpit Extraction (2LIS\_\*) to load sales, purchasing, and inventory data. Worked on data sources 0FI\_AP\_04 and 0FI\_AR\_04 for extraction and loading of data from FI to BW.

Extracted data from standard Business Content sales, PO and Inventory extractors and custom-built extractors depending on requirements

Extensive experience on production support and troubleshoot/test issues with existing reports and cubes. Involved in monitoring the performance of the system and reporting which includes performing OLAP Cache,

Aggregates, Indexes, Archiving the non-cumulative info cubes, Partitioning, etc.

Actualized various types of BEx query variables including User exit, Replacement Path, Text and formula variables. Created calculated and Restricted Key Figures, Structures, Conditions, Filters and Cell Definitions within queries, maintained Query settings and tuning.

### IBM India Pvt. Limited as Package Solution Consultant

Dec 2017 to May 2019

Implementation Project

Client: Shell Period: 12'17-05'19 Environment: SAP BI 7.5(BW/4 HANA), ECC7.0, HANA Studio (2.0).

Roles: HANA Technical Lead

#### Responsibilities:

E2E requirement gathering, design, development on HANA CVs both graphical, scripted view to perform real time data and analytics on green field implementations. Created table functions and store procedures in HANA

Performed on near real time staging BW4HANA approaches to load data into ADSOs via LSA++ Architecture from ECC/S4 HANA replicated tables

Performed delta loading to ADSO from HANA CVs and create CPs on top it to feed to Bex and SAP BOBJ, AO reports

## Accenture India Pvt. as Technical Lead

Jan 2010 to Dec 2017

### Responsibilities:

Understanding of different techniques to optimize performance of HANA views.

Good understanding of filters Input Parameters, Variables and Calculated columns and parameters in HANA Effectively implemented the design using STAR JOIN Calculation View for effective performance to process 2 billion records etc.

Client: Coke-CONA(Canada) Period: 08'15-04'16 Environment: SAP BW/BI7.4, ECC6.0, and HANA Studio (2.0),

HR. Successfactor.

Roles: HANA Technical Lead

#### Responsibilities:

Installed the Business Content Info area, Info cube, Info objects.

Expertise in preparing Technical Design Documents

Monitoring Created ADSO and open ODS views and Composite Provider etc.

Experienced in SAP Data Migration (BODS) projects

Client: Magyar Telekom (Hungary) Period: 05'14-07'15 Environment: SAP BW/BI 7.3, ECC6.0, and HANA Studio (2.0).

Roles: Sr SAP BW Developer.

### Responsibilities:

installing and creating BI objects like info objects, DSOs, Info cubes.

Data Source Enhancement according to customer requirement.

Transportation of BW Objects from Development system across the landscape through Transport Connection. Created Reports using Calculated Keyfigures, restricted keyfigures, Formulae, Conditions and Variables etc. Support Project:

Client: Loblaw (Canada) Period: 01'10-05'14 Environment: SAP BW/BI 7.0, ECC6.0, and HANA Studio (1.x)

Roles: SAP BW Developer

## Responsibilities:

Schedule daily/weekly/monthly data loads.

Daily Monitoring activities like Analyzing ABAP Dumps, Update Monitoring, Alert Monitors, and System Traces.

Daily coordinate with the offshore team to assign the tasks etc

## PWC as BW Developer Jun 2009 to Dec 2009

Support Project

Client GIL (Graphite India Limited Period: 06'09-12'09 Environment: SAP BW 3.5, ECC6.0. Roles: SAP BW Developer

Responsibilities:

Resolving the issues that occur during the Loads based on Severity Level.

Transport the objects from Development to QA for testing through charm process.

Emptying the Queues (SM13 & LBWQ) by running the V3 Jobs etc.

^ Back to Top

## **Education**

PG: MCA (Computers) from K.K Autonomous College, Berhampur in 2004

^ Back to Top

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience				
SAC					
SAP HANA					
SAP BW4HANA					
SAP BW on HANA					

SAP BW/BI
SLT
BODS

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

**Affirmative Action** 

## **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.